Hello
[music]
Hello everyone, today we will give you a review of the life savings insurance plan of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company.
This is a term insurance plan
which offers guaranteed returns. So if you are
looking for a plan with guaranteed returns for yourself, then you must watch this video. Let's
start with the entry.
Anyone can enter this policy between 1 year to 12 years.
Premium payment is
available in limited terms. 6 years, 12 years
and 10 years, 15 years
premium payment is available in regular payment.
If you take six years premium payment then it is
10 years, 15 years and if you reach the
age of 18 then it is
15 years.
In regular payment, 10 years and 15 years policy
term is available. The maturity period in this plan is
minimum 18 years and maximum 65 years.
Talking about the premium, the minimum premium
in this plan is between 20,000 to 1 lakh.
If you take a single payment voucher  If you select it
and if you select limited then it is
between 5,000 to 1 lakh. If you select ghee payment
voucher then minimum 25000 is
50 thousand rupees in limited regular payment
and maximum up to ₹10000000. You
can select MS Word. In this plan you
can also add premium in ghee and
can do it in free mode. Premium in this plan is if
you are single premium then it is
between 20000 to 25000 in bank one and
between 50,000 to 80 thousand in bank two and
between 80,000 to 1 lakh in bank three.
Whereas in annual premium, option is available between
5000 to 20000 in band one, 20,000
to 40 thousand in band two and between 40,000 to 1 lakh in bank free.
Talking about death benefit, if the policy holder dies
then whatever  The selected time shot
plus any non-Indian
bonuses will be given to the nominee of the policy holder
in the event of death and the
contract will be over.
Accidental death benefit is additional in this plan which is
inbuilt. If the policy holder dies
due to an accident, then whatever
time injury is selected will be doubled. For
example, if you have selected a time injury of Rs 5 lakh
and the death is
due to an accident, then Rs 5 lakh will be given to the
nominee of the traditional policy holder.
Talking about quality benefit,
whatever time injury is selected
plus any guaranteed bonus, all of it is given to the
policy holder on
completion of the policy term if the policy holder survives.
If for some reason you are
unable to continue your premium and pay the premium for a minimum of two
years, then whatever is the
maturity benefit
and death benefit along with the reduced premium, the benefit will be given there.
In such a situation, the nominee is presented,
and if the policyholder survives, the
maturity benefit accruing as per the reduction product will be
presented to the policyholder. If the
policyholder's policy is running on the reduce paid-up option
and the policyholder
is above 18 years of age and the policyholder
dies due to an accident, then an additional
accidental death benefit will also be offered.
Regarding the surrender value, this is a
savings amendment plan and is an insurance plan,
so surrender is never recommended.
However, if you wish to surrender your policy due to any situation, you can
surrender your policy after 2 years. A
special surrender value
option is also available in this plan. Talking about loans,
in this plan, you can take a loan against this policy with a minimum surrender value of ₹5,000 and a maximum
surrender value of ₹85.
You will have to send ₹10.05 and
click on interest.
This rate may change during the plan.  Of interest but
right now you will have to pay 10.05 percent of your interest
if you take a loan on this and
if your policy lapses
then you can revise your policy
which is within five years have been Gyanpeeth
premium. You can revive your policy by repairing it and completing the formalities of the company.
Talking about side exclusions, if the policy
holder commits suicide within one year then the
premium quality percentage is referred to the nominee. If he commits
suicide after this year then whatever
time limit is selected is given to him.
Accidental death
benefit has some exclusions which
we are putting on the screen, you can check it.
If you attempt suicide or
self-injure then no claim is given in that. If you do not commit suicide by consuming
any kind of drink, drugs or
any intoxicant and if there is no instance due to any accident then no
claim is given in this situation. Any
criminal activity  If you
participate in it, then your
family will not get any accidental death benefit tax.
If you feel
that you have not selected the right plan, then after the
free look period which is 15 days and
distance marketing period which is 30 days, you can
cancel your plan and get your money refunded.
Whatever you pay on premium, you
can claim it for tax benefit under section 80c. So this was a review of
Jeevan Bachat Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company. Like it if you
liked the video.
We keep bringing such useful information, so please
like and subscribe to our channel.
Thank you for watching.